奥地利  维也纳
VIENNA, AUSTRIA
它出现了，在贝尔格莱德！
It turned up. In Belgrade!
你明天早上就过去
You're leaving tomorrow morning.
你确定这是真品吗？
Are you sure it is the original?
我们甚至都不能确定真品是真品
We're not even sure that the original is the original.
比利时  布鲁塞尔
BRUSSELS, BELGIUM
我的儿子…萨辛卡…
My son... Sasyenka...
我知道他不是当领袖的料
I know he will never rise to be a leader.
他没那么聪明
He is not that bright.
但我觉得他可以成为一名军官
But I thought he could become an officer.
他会在我们的祖国
He will be an officer.
成为一名军官
In our homeland.
- 敬我们的祖国 - 敬我们的祖国
- To our homeland. - To our homeland.
我最小的孩子索菲亚
My youngest child, Sofia...
她是个有才华的芭蕾舞演员…
She is a talented ballet dancer...
她唱歌也很好听
She also sings beautifully.
我们会给她找个老师
We'll find her a teacher
不管是唱歌还是芭蕾
for both singing and ballet.
她会得到奖学金
She'll get a scholarship...
我还有一个请求
I have another request.
说吧
Speak.
把我埋在…
Bury me...
在一片兄弟般的东正教土地上…
In a brotherly Orthodox land.
我保证
I promise.
- 敬我们的祖国... - 敬我们的祖国..
- To our homeland... - To our homeland...
草原，我们周围的草原
Steppe, steppe all around us,
有一条小径
There's a long path in it,
在那片荒芜的草原上
In that desert steppe
一位马车夫冻僵了
A coachman was freezing.
聚集他的力量
Gathering his strength,
他的死亡时刻预示着…
His death hour he forebode...
给我
Give it to me...
巴尔干半岛的阴影
Black Sun
塔尼，塔尼! 你还活着吗，我的兄弟？
Tane, Tane! Are you alive, my brother?
不要死在我面前，塔尼！
Don't die on me, Tane!
快走! 快点！
Move it! Quickly!
你们在干什么？
What are you doing there, goddammit?
站起来，给我冲！
Lift your asses, we're going to battle!
殿下，这是塔纳西耶维奇上尉
Your Highness, this is Captain Tanasiyevich.
他必须马上去医院
He must go to the hospital immediately.
恭喜你受伤了！
Congratulations on your wound!
陪着他，等马车
Stay with him, wait for the carriage.
其他人，跟我来! 进攻！
Others, follow me! Attack!
他们跟着这个疯子冲，没有一个会回来的
They are going with this lunatic. None of them will come back.
他们都要去见上帝
They're all going to meet our Saviour.
是个男孩，一个像你一样的士兵
It's a boy, a soldier like you.
- 他们告诉我你死了 - 我没有
- They told me you were dead. - I'm not.
你在一场由疯子乔杰王子领导的战斗中牺牲了
That you were killed in a battle led by the crazy Prince Djordje.
不！
No!
闭嘴，省省力气吧
Shut up, save your breath.
这是我妻子
This is my wife.
我的孩子
And this is my child.
你死了，塔纳西耶维奇，死了!
And you're dead, Tanasiyevich. Dead! Dead...
- 谁啊? - 探长，是我，米利萨夫！
- Who is it? - Inspector, it's me, Milisav!
怎么了? 出什么事了？
What is it? What's the matter?
又发生了一起谋杀案
There's been another murder.
告诉其他人: 调查这里的每一寸土地，任何蛛丝马迹都不能放过
Tell the others: I want every stone turned, everything!
如果有任何发现，不要破坏现场，打电话给我! 明白了吗？
If you find something, don't touch it. Call me! Is that clear?
是，长官！
Yes, sir!
探长！
Inspector!
我不是告诉过你我不会再和你一起工作了吗？
Didn't I tell you I won't work with you anymore?
你以为我喜欢和你一起工作吗？
Do you think I like working with you?
探长..
Inspector...
我应该给日沃因打电话吗？
Should I call Zhivoyin?
- 米利萨夫，头在哪里? - 在里面
- Milisav, where is the head? - Inside.
我不想让你觉得我这么做是出于怨恨…
I don't want you to think I'm doing this out of spite...
局长坚持要我和你一起调查这个案子
Commissioner insisted that I investigate this case with you.
我自己就能调查
I'm doing this alone.
随你便，我不需要你
Do what you want, I don't need you.
请进
Here.
看起来像是用军刀砍的
Looks like this was done with a sabre.
或者一把斧头？
Or maybe an axe?
军刀的可能性更大
Though sabre is more likely.
这里在干嘛? 某种变装舞会？
What happened here? Some sort of a costume party?
不，他们每天都穿成这样
No, they dress up like that every day.
这些目击者怎么办？
What shall we do with the witnesses?
他们人太多了，我们不能每个都审问
There are too many of them. We can't question all of them.
- 日沃因 - 什么事，先生？
- Zhivoyin. - Yes, sir?
把他们的身份证收走
Take their ID's.
告诉他们明天去局里
Tell them to come to prison tomorrow.
我们会在那里询问他们
We'll question them there.
好主意，你想让我现在就审问她丈夫吗？
Great idea. Do you want me to question the husband now?
在我回来之前不要询问任何人，明白吗？
Do not question anyone until I get back. Understood?
- 所有人都不准离开大厅 - 好的！
- No one leaves the hall. - Okay!
谁让你进来的？
Who let you in here?
我要尿尿
I need to pee.
乔娃！
Jova!
等他尿完再把他带回来
Wait for him to finish and get him back there.
探长，教授…
Excuse me, inspector. The professor...
抱歉，他们把我们关在这里好几个小时
I'm sorry, they want to keep us here for hours,
我丈夫病得很重
and my husband is really ill.
我知道这种情况下私下联系警方是不道德的
I know it's unethical to use private contacts with the police
但我和我妻子整晚都在这儿数选票…
but my wife and I were here all night, counting the votes...
如果你还有其他的问题，欢迎来我家喝咖啡
If you have more questions, drop by for a cup of coffee.
我们得走了，他得吃药了
We have to go now, he must take his medicine.
没关系，谢谢
It's alright. Thank you.
再见
Goodbye.
夫人，你认为是谁杀了她？
What do you think, Ma'am, who tarnished his soul with a sin?
我不知道..
I don't know...
但这种惨烈的死法应该留给共产主义者和冒险家
but such a terrible death is for communists and adventurers,
而不是一位善良又受人尊敬的女人
but this is simply not for such a nice and respectable woman.
这是不对的
It's just not right.
- 玛雅，不要 - 这是宾客名单
- Maya, don't. - Here's the guest list.
也许你现在想审问她丈夫？
Maybe you'd like to question the husband now?
那个女人穿的裙子和死者一样
That woman is wearing the same dress as our victim.
- 沃因 - 这里不行
- Voyin. - Not here.
我会没事的，别担心
I'll be okay, don't worry.
在她旁边的是受害者的丈夫，州检察长沃因·朱基奇
Beside her is the victim's husband, Voyin Djukich, the state prosecutor.
我知道他是检察长
I know who the state prosecutor is.
朱基奇先生，我是塔纳西耶维奇探长
Mr. Djukich, I'm Inspector Tanasiyevich.
请接受我的哀悼
Accept my condolences.
塔纳西耶维奇探长
Inspector Tanasiyevich.
- 玛雅 · 达维多维奇 - 很高兴见到你
- Maya Davidovich. - Nice to meet you.
对不起，你能留下来一会儿吗？
Excuse me, could you please stay for a moment?
- 我也有几个问题要问你 - 为什么？
- I have a few questions for you too. - Why?
因为我是探长
Because I'm the inspector.
我知道你还在震惊中，但是你能不能试着回忆一下
I know you're still in shock, but can you please try to remember
你最后一次见到你妻子是什么时候？
when you last saw your wife alive?
我真的记不清了
I really don't know...
在最后一支舞之前，大厅很拥挤，音乐很吵…
Before the last dance. It was crowded, the music...
我甚至没有注意到她什么时候出门
I didn't even notice when she went out.
你没和她跳舞？
And you didn't dance with her?
他和我跳舞
He danced with me.
我也是这么想的
That's what I thought.
你这话是什么意思，探长？
What do you mean by that, inspector?
探长，你最好先问我话
Inspector, it'd be better if you questioned me first.
他还没缓过来
He's in shock.
- 你认识死者吗? - 认识
- Alright. Did you know the victim? - Yes.
我们不是朋友，但我们有一个共同的熟人圈子
We weren't friends, but we had a common circle of acquaintances.
你们还有什么共同点吗？
Did you have anything else in common?
比如？
Like?
- 服装 - 是的
- The costume. - Yes.
你最好问问我的裁缝
It would be best if you asked my seamstress why Violet
为什么维奥莱塔让她做了一件和我一样的服装
asked her for a replica of my costume.
让开! 快点，让开！
Move aside! Go on, move!
朱基奇先生，请接受我最深切的哀悼
Mr. Djukich, please accept my deepest condolences.
放心，我们会找到凶手的
Rest assured that we will find who did this.
正义会得到伸张
Justice will be done.
局长，我们正在..
Commissioner, we were in the middle...
很晚了
It's late.
如果可能的话，请回家休息一下
Please, go home and get some rest, if possible. Get some sleep.
探长会打电话给你安排问话
Inspector will call you to make arrangements for your questioning.
- 安排? - 请吧
- To make the arrangements? - Please.
- 这是我们唯一能做的了 - 谢谢局长
- That's the least we can do. - Thank you, commissioner.
- 我很抱歉 - 探长
- I'm so sorry. - Inspector.
塔尼！
Tane!
对不起
Sorry.
他是国家检察官! 日夫科维奇让我来干涉调查
Jesus, he's the state prosecutor! Zhivkovich called me to intervene.
如果事实证明朱基奇就是凶手，他会干涉吗？
Will he intervene if it turns out that Djukich is the murderer?
你认为像他这种地位的人会那样杀死他的妻子吗？
Do you think that a man of his stature would kill his wife like that?
别管那个了，看看这个人
Never mind the stature, look at the man.
如果是那个女孩说服他的呢？
What if this girl talked him into it?
- 你知道她是他的情妇? - 他是她的情夫
- You know she is his mistress? - He is her mistress.
那是阿瑟妮 · 达维多维奇的女儿
That's Arseniye Davidovich's daughter.
她很有钱，有两个博士学位
She's loaded, has two PhD's.
下次你想做什么事，先向我报告
Next time you want to do something, report to me first.
明白了吗！
Is that clear?!
探长，我们拿到了所有的文件
Inspector, we took all the documents.
- 这是宾客名单 - 很好
- Here's the guest list. - Good.
米利萨夫应该跟着玛雅 · 达维多维奇
Milisav should go after Maya Davidovich.
你听到他说的了
You heard the man.
别让她离开你的视线！
Don't let her out of your sight!
我也觉得她很可疑
I also thought she was suspicious.
我想我应该留在这里，试着找到武器
I reckoned I should stay here, to try to find the weapon.
随便你，我要去睡觉了
Do what you want, I'm going to bed.
米伦特耶！
Milentye!
你们怎么来了? 为什么？
Why are you standing there, man? Why?
你们是我最不想见到的人
You're the last persons I wanted to see...
欢迎，你好！
Welcome, shalom, hello!
不是同一种货吗？
It's not the same goods?
马其顿的货
Macedonian.
马其顿？
Macedonian?
所以他们说的是真的..
So, it's true what they say...
马其顿的鸦片比土耳其的好？
That the Macedonian opium is better than the Turkish?
土耳其鸦片要次一些
Turkish opium might be weaker,
但是土耳其人用一天的时间用火车运走了
but the Turks transfer it by train in a day.
马其顿的鸦片用商队的骆驼和驴子运货
And Macedonian opium arrives on camels and donkeys,
而商队受到马其顿土匪的保护
while the caravans are protected by Macedonian bandits.
想想办法
Well, think of something.
这是值得的
It will be worth your while,
我也有得赚
as well as mine.
我们会考虑的
We'll think about it.
再见
Goodbye.
如果宪兵不保护他们
If gendarmes weren't protecting them,
- 十个人就能打垮他们 - 我们不能硬拼
- we'd crush them with ten men. - We can't go to war with them too,
- 老板正在想办法 - 可不是吗
- but the boss is working on it. - I'd love that.
多布里沃伊坑死我了
Dobrivoye, you screwed me!
如果不是他，他们永远不会找到我
If it weren't for him, they'd never have found me.
你不用担心多布里沃伊，担心你自己吧
Don't you worry about Dobrivoye, look out for yourself.
- 快把车开回来! - 好吧
- And get this truck back, come on! - Okay, fine.
FIGARO 理发店
Barber shop FIGARO
有人在吗？
Anybody there?
国家检察长的妻子惨遭谋杀
BLOODY MURDER OF THE STATE PROSECUTOR'S WIFE
别哭了，孩子，你让我头疼
Stop weeping, son. You're giving me a headache.
来自莫斯科的问候
Greetings from Moscow.
圣坛上没有别的东西了吗？
There was nothing else left in the altar?
没了，都拿去吧，我什么都不需要了
No. Take it all. I don't need anything anymore.
我活够了！
I don't want to live anymore!
别这么说，我的孩子..
Don't talk like that, my son...
小心你的愿望
Be careful what you wish for.
现在，做个好孩子..
Now, be a good boy...
告诉我你对第42件物品做了什么？
and tell me what have you done with the 42nd object?
有一条项链..
There was a necklace...
在盒子里吗？
Was it in the box?
是的
Yes, it was.
你把它卖给谁了，孩子？
Whom did you sell it to, my son?
我没有卖
I didn't sell it.
我把它送给了…
I gave it...
我心爱的女人
to the woman I love!
她现在在哪儿？
And where is she now?
如果死因很明显，那么说明死因就太愚蠢了
It'd be silly to specify the cause of death when it's so obvious.
凶手有使用刀刃的技巧
The killer has a skill in handling the blade.
整洁的外科手术切口
Clean surgical cut.
如果你抓到他，把他带到这里来做我的助手
If you catch him, bring him here to be my assistant.
把她换掉
This one is no good.
别往心里去，我的同事对我甚至更糟
Don't sweat it, my colleague treats me even worse.
她可能被下药了
She could've been drugged or poisoned;
砍头可不容易
it's not easy to cut a head.
她会抗拒的，血液检查会有更多结果
She'd have resisted, but we'll know more when we get the blood tests.
我现在就把报告给你
I'll give you the report now.
- 给你 - 谢谢你，博雅纳，你太棒了
- That's it. Here you go. - Thank you, Boyana, you're wonderful.
你在洛桑学过法医学？
You studied forensics in Lausanne?
是的，我很荣幸能在那里读书
Yes, it was a great privilege.
那是什么感觉？
What was it like?
一切都不同了..
Everything is different...
对人的理解，对工作的奉献..
people, dedication to work...
也许有空我们可以去散散步
Maybe we could go for a walk some time.
为什么不呢？
Why not?
没有附加条件，我只是觉得你可能需要…
No strings attached. I just thought you might need
一个贝尔格莱德的导游，因为你离开很久了
a guide through Belgrade since you haven't been here in a while...
是的，当然
Yes, of course.
不过我对贝尔格莱德很熟悉
I'm familiar with Belgrade though.
好吧，那就算了
Okay, never mind then.
再见
Goodbye.
祝你今天过得愉快
Have a nice day.
嗨，塔尼！
Hi Tane!
让我尝尝你的白兰地
Leave me alone with your plum brandy.
你在任何地方都找不到这个
You won't find this anywhere.
请给我一份卷心菜
A cabbage, please.
当然，这个不错... 别
Sure. Here's nice one... Don't.
免费的
It's on the house.
找一个这样的女人——漂亮，成熟，脸红
And find a woman like that – beautiful, ripe and blush.
- 而且很丰满 - 塔纳西耶维奇！
- And plump. - Tanasiyevich!
- 我妻子在哪? - 再来几个
- Where is my wife? - A few more, please.
你听到我说什么了吗！
Did you hear what I'm saying?!
她已经不在我的管辖范围内了！
She is not in my jurisdiction anymore!
走开！
Go away!
别装傻了，她不在阿姨家
Stop playing dumb. She's not at her aunt's,
也不在她妈妈那里，她在哪儿？
not at her mother's, nowhere. Where is she?
如果你少打她一顿，她就不会跑掉了
If you had beaten her less, she wouldn't have run away.
我打她是因为我有这个权利
I beat her because I have the right to.
如果你再打她一顿，她就会在家里等你了
Had you beaten her more, she'd be at home, waiting for you.
你凭什么教训我? 你这个讨厌的警察！
Who are you to lecture me? You stinking cop!
你碰我一下试试，今天乔洛维奇不会来帮你！
Lay your finger on me and no Djolovich will help you!
我是皇家军官！
I'm a royal officer!
你是个王室白痴! 你他妈的到底想怎样？
You're a royal dickhead! What the fuck do you want?
如果她来找你，请让她回到我身边
If she comes to you, please tell her to come back to me.
孩子们整天哭个不停，我不知道该怎么办
Children are crying all day long, I don't know what to do.
我求你了
I'm begging you.
探长，需要帮忙吗？
Inspector, do you need any help?
怎么了，斯维塔？
What do you want, Sveta?
日沃因让我告诉你
Zhivoyin told me to let you know
米利萨夫打电话说那位女士要出远门
that Milisav called and said the lady was going on a trip.
我不知道我什么时候会回来，但是拜托
I don't know if or when I'll come back, but please,
- 如果他们想接管银行... - 别担心
- if they try to take over the bank... - Don't worry.
很快就没有东西可以接管了
Soon there'll be nothing to take over.
- 阿佩奇叔叔 - 别叫我叔叔
- Uncle Tache. - Don't Uncle Tache me.
你挑起了一场毫无意义的战争
You started a meaningless war,
而现在你却要去维也纳吃萨赫蛋糕
and now you're off to Vienna to eat Sachertorte or what...
等我回来再告诉你们，相信我，我别无选择
I'll tell you all when I get back. Believe me, I had no choice.
好吧！
Alright!
你需要的东西都带了吗? 你的护照？
Did you take everything you need? Your passport?
Mr. Papahagi, a policeman is looking for her.
帕帕哈吉先生，外面有个警察正在找她
- 下午好，有什么可以帮您的吗? - 下午好，我在找
Good afternoon, how may I help you? Good afternoon, I'm looking for
玛雅 · 达维多维奇小姐，我听说她在这里工作
Miss Maya Davidovich. I was told that she works here.
你被误导了
You were misinformed.
我们所有人都为达维多维奇小姐工作
All of us here work for Miss Davidovich.
塔纳西耶维奇督察，刑侦部
Inspector Tanasiyevich, crimes dept.
我想见见她，问她几个问题
I'd like to see her and ask her a few questions.
很高兴见到你，我是塔基 · 帕帕哈吉
Pleasure to meet you. My name is Tache Papahagi.
我是这家银行的经理，也是达维多维奇的家庭律师
I'm the manager of this bank and Davidovich family lawyer.
有什么问题尽管问我
Anything you need to ask, you can ask me.
没事的，塔基
It's alright, Taki.
探长，请进
Inspector, please come in.
抱歉不请自来
Sorry to come unannounced,
但你似乎没有兑现昨晚的承诺
but last night it didn't seem like you had any commitments in your life.
你看起来更像是犯罪的受害者
And you seem more like a victim of a crime,
而不是一个本该破案的人
than someone who is supposed to solve it.
朱基奇太太知道你和她丈夫的事吗？
Did Mrs. Djukich know about you and her husband?
如果你都能知道的话，我想她也能知道
Well, if you managed to figure it out, I'm sure she did too.
是你杀了维奥莱塔 · 朱基奇吗？
And did you kill Violeta Djukich?
我？
Me?
是的
Yes.
我为什么要杀她，探长？
Why would I kill her, inspector?
这样好跟沃因上床？
Why would then push Voyin into my bed?
是我在干扰她的生活，而不是反过来
I was disturbing her, not the other way around.
你母亲把你教育得很好
I see your mother raised you well.
她没有时间教育我
She didn't have the time to raise me,
她在我很小的时候就去世了
she died when I was little.
小姐
Miss...
没事，佩多尼耶维奇探长这就要走了
It's okay, Inspector Petroniyevich is on his way.
塔纳西耶维奇，是的，我正准备走
Tanasiyevich. Yes, I am.
谢谢你的合作
Thank you for your cooperation.
请把你的护照给我好吗？
Can you please give me your passport?
探长，我要知道为什么？
Inspector, I demand to know why?
这是调查中的常规程序
It's a usual procedure during an ongoing investigation.
调查？
Investigation?
你最好把你的护照给我，否则我不得不逮捕你
You better give me your passport or I will have to arrest you.
非常感谢
Thank you very much.
暂时不离开贝尔格莱德是明智的
It'd be wise not to leave Belgrade for a while.
我不想再到处找你了，再见
I don't want to have to search for you. Goodbye.
我要取消去维也纳的机票
I will cancel the ticket to Vienna.
亲爱的，你该搬到老房子去了
Sweetheart, it's time for you to move to the old house.
在那里很难监视你
It's hard to keep an eye on you here.
我宁愿死也不去那儿
I'd rather die than go there.
我知道你是好意，但是拜托
I know you mean well, but please.
我必须一个人面对这件事
I have to do this alone.
大家急什么? 不... 等等..
What's the rush, people? No... Wait...
请把身份证还给我的夫人，她不舒服
Please, my madam is unwell, give her ID back.
对不起，这是违法的
Sorry. It's against the law.
她必须到这里来做笔录
She must come here to give a statement.
一旦她做完笔录，马上就能拿回她的文件
Once she does that, she'll get her documents back.
但是..
But...
- 请排队! - 我今晚必须去卢布尔雅那！
- Wait for your turn, please! - I have to be in Ljubljana tonight!
先做笔录，然后去任何你想去的地方！
Wait for your documents and then go wherever you want!
- 对不起! - 腾点地方出来！
- Excuse me! - Make some room!
怎么样？
How's it going?
这些人毫无纪律，都想第一个进去
These people have no discipline. They all want to get in first.
好吧，加快速度
Alright, speed it up a little.
放松，别急，放松... 退后！
Easy, easy... Back off!
就这些? 你还有什么要补充的吗？
Is that all? Do you have anything to add?
有一点，你结婚了吗？
Yes. Are you married?
请别误会，你看你这么帅
Please, don't get me wrong. I'm looking at how handsome
我有个侄女，一个很好的女孩..
you are and I have this niece, a wonderful girl...
再见，夫人
Goodbye, Madam.
太不可思议了，没人看到有用的线索
This is incredible. No one saw anything.
看着他们的眼睛
Look them in the eye.
重要的不是他们说了什么，而是他们怎么说
It's not what they say, it's how they say it.
你们两个过来！
You two, come here!
有人抢劫了朱基奇先生的家
Someone robbed Mr. Djukich's home.
别小题大做，天黑以后再去那里
Don't make a circus out of it, go there after dark
仔细检查现场
and inspect the scene discretely.
以一种文明的方式
In a civilized manner, Pletikosich.
- 老大！老大！- 什么事！
- Boss, boss, boss! - What?!
- 有人找你，他们说情况紧急 - 什么情况？
- It's your men, they say it's urgent. - What?
到底要干什么？
What do they want?
啊，多布里沃伊，好孩子，你做了什么？
Ah, Dobrivoye, my son. What have you done?
我做了什么？
What have I done?
你捅篓子了
You became expensive.
三十袋最纯的马其顿鸦片
Thirty bags of purest Macedonian opium.
我会赔偿一切，告诉那个僧人
I'll pay for all of it, everything. Tell the Monk...
闭嘴! 闭嘴！
Shut up! Shut up!
他有话对你说
He has a message for you...
握住他的手
Hold his hand...
枪，枪！
Gun, gun!
你被解雇了！
You're fired!
下一次，不要在我做爱的时候打断我
Next time, don't interrupt me during a shag.
把钥匙给我
Give me the key.
门没锁
It's unlocked.
楼上
Up.
站住！
Stop!
趴下！
Down! Get down!
你是什么人？
Who are you?
通知所有我们的人，将军会准时到达
Inform all of our men that the general will be here on time.
召集所有人来欢迎他! 包括你！
Gather everyone to welcome him! Including you!
公寓有人住，一位来自维也纳的客人住在那里
The apartment is occupied. A guest from Vienna is staying there
我是费奥多 · 斯切尔巴斯基上尉
This is Captain Fyodor Stcherbatsky.
你有一个小时的时间清理公寓
You have an hour to clear the apartment.
一个小时，一分钟也不能多！
An hour, not a minute more!
别逼我过去
Don't make me come there.
- 阿廖沙在哪? - 他还没到
- Where is Alyosha? - He hasn't arrived yet.
我们走! 快点！
Let's go! Come on!
米利萨夫！
Milisav!
快，这边! 拿担架和毛巾来
Quick, over here! Bring a stretcher and a towel.
把他从车里弄出来，拿条毛巾来! 快点！
Get him out of the car. Bring a towel! Come on, man!
拿条毛巾来! 快点！
Bring a towel! Come on, man!
清洗他的伤口
Wash his wound.
毛巾！
Towel!
没什么好看的，回去做你的事吧！
Nothing to see here, get back to your business!
我最亲爱的薇奥莱塔，爱你的阿廖沙
My dearest Violeta, love, Alyosha.
这些信是你寄给她的吗？
Did you send these letters to her?
你叫阿廖沙吗？
Is your name Alyosha?
你听到了吗? 你是俄罗斯人吗？
Do you hear me? Are you Russian?
你叫什么名字？
What's your name?
我记得那天晚上，我看到你和费奥多 · 斯切尔巴斯基在一起
I believe I saw you the other night with Fyodor Stcherbatsky.
我会给他打电话问问他是不是少了一个自己人
I'll call him to ask if he's missing one of his own.
我说什么来着? 退后，快点！
What did I say? Back off, move! Come on!
给他包扎伤口！
Dress his wound!
把他放到担架上，关起来！
Put him on the stretcher and take him into custody!
我叫阿列克谢 · 格鲁什尼茨基，库班军团的中尉
My name is Aleksei Grushnitsky, lieutenant of the Kuban Corps,
服从沃兰赫尔将军
under the command of General Vrangel.
我会告诉你一切
I'll tell you everything.
但有一个条件
But there's one condition.
不能让我的指挥官知道这件事
My commanding officer mustn't know about this.
别拿枪指着我! 你想杀了我？
Don't wave that gun at me! You want to kill me?
对不起
I'm sorry.
- 你为什么闯进那栋房子? - 我没有
- Why did you break into the house? - I didn't.
维奥莱塔给了我钥匙
Violeta gave me the keys.
我到那儿时，门已经坏了
When I got there, the door was already broken.
我开枪打的那个人是谁？
And who is the guy I shot? Who is he?
我不知道..
I don't know...
也许他先我一步闯进了那里
Maybe he broke into the house before me.
阿廖沙
Alyosha,
是你杀了维奥莱塔 · 朱基奇吗？
did you kill Violeta Djukich?
不是
No.
我爱她
I loved her.
晚上好，费奥多先生，你好吗？
Good evening, Mr. Fyodor. How are you?
抬杆
Raise the ramp.
你好吗，埃芬迪·塞夫凯特？
How are you, Effendi Sevket?
事情总是会好起来的，我的朋友
Things could always be better, my friend.
打开
Open it.
谢谢你
Thank you.
旅途愉快
Have a nice trip.
我们还要拍他们马屁拍多久？
How long are we going to kiss their asses?
他们一点礼貌都没有！
They're so rude!
拉亚奇基教授，打扰一下，有位维也纳来的先生
Professor Rayachky, excuse me, a gentleman is here from Vienna.
他有急事找你
He wants to speak with you urgently.
晚上好，拉亚奇基伯爵，弗莱舍伯爵派我来的
Good evening, Count Rayachky. Count Fleischer has sent me.
他有点急事
He wants to speak with you urgently.
当我们寻求帮助时
When we asked for help,
当我需要得到信息，物流和资金的时候…
I hoped for information, logistics and money.
加布里埃尔 · 马赫特，为您效劳
Gabriel Macht, at your service.
对不起，我不知道..
I'm sorry, I didn't know...
我以为..
I thought...
您能来帮助我们，我感到非常荣幸
It is a great honour to have you here to help us.
我不是来帮忙的，我是来接手的
I'm not here to help. I came to take over.
当然，您会得到所需的一切
Of course. You will get everything you need.
没有必要夸大礼貌，伯爵
There's no need for exaggerated courtesy, Count.
我有足够的斯拉夫血统，更看重优质白兰地
I have enough Slavic blood to have more respect for a good brandy
而不是恭维
than for compliments.
但前提是要有足够的德国人来完成我的工作
But enough German to finish my job first.
那么，这就是代号？
So, this is the designation?
- 是的 - 你确定吗
- Yes. - And you're sure that's it.
不
No.
但是当财宝从教堂被偷走的时候，它就出现了
But it appeared when the treasure was stolen from the church.
- 罗曼诺夫的宝藏 - 所以还有希望？
- The Romanov treasure. - So, there is hope?
不仅仅是希望
More than just hope,
我们已经采取了一些措施
that's why we have already taken certain measures.
我听说了，那么，谁是负责人？
So I've heard. And, who's in charge?
一个非常有能力并且有责任心的人
A very capable and responsible man.
- 我想见见他 - 当然
- I'd like to meet him. - Of course.
告诉我，我什么时候能见到老大？
Tell me, when do I get to meet the head?
要先进行入会仪式
First, the initiation ceremony.
是的，当然
Yes. Of course.
那么，把白兰地拿出来吧
Now, bring the brandy.
玛丽亚！
Maria!
晚上好
Good evening.
- 你累了吗? - 有点
- Are you tired? - A bit.
现在该怎么办？
And now what?
我们先吃晚饭吧
Let's have supper to begin with.
我们还要这样多久？
How long shall we go on like this?
我不知道
I don't know.
但是让我们尽量把生活过好吧
But let's make it good while it lasts.
索尼娅
Sonya...
你的孩子在家等你
Your children are home. Waiting for you.
- 号啕大哭 - 别这样
- Crying. - Oh, c'mon.
这不能怪他们
They're not to blame.
也不能怪我
I'm not either.
这不公平
It's not fair.
我不知道你还活着
You know I didn't know you were alive.
- 你知道我会等的 - 我知道
- You know I would have waited? - I know.
你到底想要我怎样? ! 你在耍我！
So what do you want from me?! You're playing games with me!
你在跟我玩游戏！
You're playing games with me!
拜托
Please, for God's sake.
把钥匙给我
Give me the key.
我想永远结束这一切
I want to end this forever.
不! 我不会给你钥匙的！
No! I'm not giving you the key!
绝不！
I'm not giving you the key!
我走了，一会儿见
I'm going, see you soon.
我知道，早告诉过你了
I knew, I told you that would happen.
但是没人听我的，斯坦科！
But no one listens to me! Stanko!
夫人？
Madam?
是我，你去哪儿了？
It's me, where have you been?
- 你在这儿干什么，夫人? - 别叫我夫人
- What are you doing here, Madam? - Don't you Madam me.
都上过床了还叫什么夫人
There's no Madam after shagging.
你想要什么？
What do you want?
我想要回我的孩子
I want my child back.
是你的错，是你自己问的
It's your fault, you asked about it.
从那以后我几乎没有睡过觉
I have barely slept since.
那个恶棍把我肚子搞大了，还带走了孩子
The thug got me pregnant and took the kid.
说我是人渣..
Says I'm scum...
他不想让我的丑事传到他家里！
He doesn't want my dirt in his family!
- 而你是个警察 - 探长
- And you're a cop. - Inspector.
是的，那你帮我探探我儿子在哪里
Yeah. Well, inspect this.
我很想帮你，但我正在处理一个大案子
Gladly, but I'm in the middle of a big case
- 我没时间 - 真的吗？
- and I haven't got the time. - Oh, really?
但是你有时间跟我翻云覆雨三个钟头？
But you had time for a three-hour shag?
好好好，你到底想怎样？
Okay, what do you want?
这是孩子的出生证明，我还有目击证人
This is the baby's birth certificate. I also have witnesses.
一个接生婆和一个牧师，你问问他们就知道了
A midwife and a priest. Just say the word.
- What's your name? - Mara
- 你叫什么名字？ - 玛拉
玛拉，告诉我，孩子的父亲是谁？
Tell me, Mara, what is the father's name?
这就是问题所在，我不知道
That's the problem, I don't know.
好吧，我会尽力的，再见
Okay, I'll do my best. Goodbye.
好的，顺便过来找我
Okay. And drop by.
咱都一家人
Don't be a stranger.
你知道在哪能找到我
I'll be around.
好吧，然后发生了什么？
Yeah, okay. What happened next?
我真的不知道还能告诉你什么？
I really don't know what else to tell you?
我们喝酒，跳舞，灯光忽明忽暗
We drank, danced, the lights went off and on.
等等，灯到底是开着还是关着的? 你根本就是胡说八道
Wait, did they turn them on or off? You're not making any sense.
是舞厅的灯球
That was the concept of the ball.
照到别的地方，再照回来，然后我们就看到了那个头
First they went off, then back on. Then we saw the head.
你认识维奥莱塔 · 朱基奇吗？
Did you know Violeta Djukich?
是的，但是不太熟
I did, but we weren't close.
她是我们艺术团的赞助人之一
She was one of the benefactors of our arts group.
我们都是她的“拜占庭”艺术团成员
We're all members of her "Byzantium" art group.
把你的帽子摘下来
Take your hat off.
玛雅 · 达维多维奇中途有离开过派对吗？
Did Maya Davidovich leave the party?
我怎么知道? ！
How should I know?!
你去问她啊! 别再骚扰我们了！
Ask her! Stop harassing us!
我必须回去画画了！
My painting has to be ready for the exhibition!
坐下! 别喊了！
Sit down! Stop yelling!
你们都是画家？
You're all painters?
- 我是个雕塑家 - 我是个摄影师
- I'm a sculptress. - And I'm a photographer.
那巧了
You don't say.
你不会有派对上的照片吧？
You wouldn't have photos from the party?
当然有，我是被雇来拍照的
Of course I would, I was hired to eternalize the event.
太好了，你们可以走了，除了你
Perfect. You're free to go, except for you.
教授... 探长
Professor... Inspector,
我还没来得及冲洗照片
I didn't have the time to develop the photographs.
也许我和他们一起回去更好？
Maybe it'd be better if I go with them?
可以等等
It can wait.
过来
Come over here.
你这些瘀伤是从哪儿来的？
Where did you get all those bruises?
有些丈夫不喜欢他们的妻子在相机前搔首弄姿
Some husbands don't like it when their wives pose for me.
你还是个讨女人喜欢的男人
My, my... You're a real ladies' man.
维奥莱塔 · 朱基奇是你的模特吗？
Was Violeta Djukich your model, by any chance?
不，不... 我从没拍过她
No, no... Never.
探长，局长要见你..
Inspector, the commissioner wants to see you...
你没看见我在询问目击证人吗？
Can't you see I'm questioning a witness?
他说他有急事
He says he's in a hurry.
好的，把手给我
Okay. Give me your hand.
- 什么? - 坐下
- What? - Sit down.
喝点东西，我马上回来
Have a drink, I'll be right back.
来吧，我们走！
C'mon, let's go!
但我还要去…
But I need to develop the...
你没睡好吗？
You haven't had much sleep?
也难怪，你情人的妻子就像某种亲戚
Yeah, your lover's wife is like some kind of relative.
我只是想让你放松一下
I just wanted you to relax a bit.
你觉得是谁把她的头砍下来的？
What do you think, who could have cut her head off?
就像中世纪一样
Like in the Middle Ages.
- 也许是沃因雇了杀手? - 不是
- Maybe Voyin hired someone? - No.
维奥莱塔是因我而死的
Violeta was killed because of me.
内文把底片的事告诉了一伙罪犯
Neven told some criminals about the negatives.
跟他们说底片在我这
He told them they were mine.
他们可能因为服装杀错人了
They probably confused us because of the costume.
亲爱的上帝，你确定吗？
Dear lord, are you sure?
死的应该是我，现在一清二楚了
It should have been me. It's as clear as day.
- 愚蠢的白痴! - 我才是白痴！
- Stupid idiot! - I'm an idiot! I am!
我告诉过你别再耍花招了
I told you to stop those shenanigans.
你以为你可以靠一帮瘾君子和同性恋
You thought you could blackmail the head of secret service?
就能勒索将军？
With the help of none other than your opium junkies and fags.
但是我已经全部搞定了
But I had it all figured out.
我甚至确保他们永远不会发现是我干的
I even made sure they never find out it was me.
你想得很清楚，不是吗？
You figured it out really good, didn't you?
现在怎么办？
And now what?
你的人什么时候过来？
When's your guy coming over?
我到底为什么要跟你引荐他？
Why on earth did I even mention him to you?
我跟你说过他会为了自己的利益而利用这些照片
I told you he'd use the photos for his own benefit.
相信我，我对他有个计划
Believe me, I have a proposition for him.
现在告诉我，他什么时候来？
Please, tell me, is he coming and when?
我甚至不知道他是否还活着！
I don't even know if he's alive, let alone if he's coming!
他现在应该已经到了
He should have already been here by now.
我已经等他好几天了
I have been waiting for him for days.
对不起
I'm sorry.
如果我让康斯坦丁去问将军呢？
What if I told Konstantin to ask the general?
也许他忘了你爸爸是谁，也许他会同情你？
Maybe he forgot who your dad was, maybe he'll take pity on you?
他欠康斯坦丁一个人情，他不会拒绝的？
He owes a favour to Konstantin and he won't say no to him.?
他肯定会的，谢谢你，克里斯塔
He will, for sure. Thank you, Krista.
我会把那些该死的底片还给内文,
I'll return the bloody negatives to Neven,
然后我就消失，直到尘埃落定
And then I'll disappear. Until the dust settles.
你可以去布达佩斯
You could hop over to Budapest.
我在那边有熟人，他会帮你的
I have a guy there, and he has a nice colleague for you.
怎么样？
What do you say?
你们会闹出丑闻的！
You're going to make a scandal!
朱基奇正在对马其顿内部革命组织提起诉讼
Now that Djukich has a case against the IMRO.
那个俄国人真的..
Did that Russian really...
是的，他是小三
Yes. He fucked her.
我应该因此起诉他吗？
Am I supposed to indict him for that?
不，不! 你有证据吗？
No, no! Do you have any proof of it?
有，首先他有钥匙
Yes. He had the key,
并且我们找到了他给她的信和项链
and we found letters and the necklace
他们有一腿
he gave to the madam. They were having an affair..
那就这样吧
Here's what we'll do.
把信和项链给我，其他的就算了
Bring me the letters and the necklace and forget the rest.
好吧，但我得把这个写进报告里
Okay, but I'll have to put that in my report.
我叫你写什么你就写什么！
You will write what I tell you to write!
那个俄国人是个贼！
The Russian is a thief!
朱基奇给他妻子买了这条项链,
Djukich bought the necklace for his wife,
你还没有看到这些信件! 明白了吗？
and you haven't seen the letters! Is that clear?
或者你想被炒鱿鱼？
Or maybe you want to get fired?
探长，我们不能就这么算了
Inspector, we cannot agree to this.
必须向某人报告这件事
We have to report this to someone.
拿着这个
Here, take this.
我不能再为我们两个人开枪了
I can't shoot for both of us anymore.
谢谢你
Thank you.
不用再叫我长官，我们现在是一条船上的了
And stop calling me sir, we're in this together now.
探长！
Inspector!
我靠！摄影师！你在这儿干嘛？
Holy crap, photographer! What are you doing here?
没有人来问我是否口渴
No one came to check up on me, ask me if I'm thirsty,
- 需不需要上厕所... - 带他去冲洗胶卷
if I want to go to the loo... Take him to develop the film.
等等... 拜托
Wait... Come on.
这不公平，我饿晕了，手都麻了
It's not fair, I'm hungry. I became numb.
你不会真的要把项链交给局长吧？
You're not really going to give that to the commissioner?
命令就是命令
An order is an order.
你能快点吗？
Can you hurry up, please?
- 你有烟吗? - 没有，我不抽烟
- Do you have a cigarette? - No, I don't smoke.
抽点别的吗？
Something else to smoke?
你疯了吗? 我是个警察
Are you mad? I'm an inspector.
正因为你是警察我才问的
That's why I ask.
你需要多少时间来冲洗这些照片？
How much time do you need to develop those photos?
一两个小时
An hour or two.
还有三张颁奖之前的照片
I had three more photos left
但是…
for the winning costume, but...
你也看到了
You saw what happened...
- 那是谁? - 谁？
- Who is it? - Who?
去商店里等我
Wait for me in the shop.
先生，我只是想问你一件事！
Sir, I just want to ask you something!
你在这儿干什么？
What are you doing here?
万岁! 俄罗斯万岁! 俄罗斯万岁！
Bravo! Bravo! Russia! Russia!
我们的救世主，愿上帝保佑你身体健康
Our saviour, may God bless you with good health.
克拉斯诺夫先生
Mr. Krasnov...
谢天谢地你来了，他们告诉你了吗？
Thank God you came. Did they tell you?
我都知道了，别担心
I know everything, don't worry.
你在贝尔格莱德有什么新建筑吗？
Are you building anything new in Belgrade?
我们一直都很忙
We've been pretty busy.
希望不久我们就能在我们亲爱的俄罗斯开始建设
Hopefully, soon we will be building in our dear Russia.
欢迎，将军
Welcome, general.
既然你来了，你一定要来看我们的首映
Now that you're here, you have to come and see our premiere.
好了，够了! 出去！
Alright, enough! Get out!
兄弟姐妹们！
Brothers and sisters!
要有信心！
Have faith!
我们将拯救我们亲爱的俄罗斯！
We will save our dear Russia!
我们要在春天发动进攻！
We're launching an offensive in the spring!
内文！
Neven!
沃兰赫尔! 沃兰赫尔! 沃兰赫尔! 沃兰赫尔！
Vrangel! Vrangel! Vrangel! Vrangel!
上帝与我们同在